Okoye Chibuike Dennis

☑ okoyedennis7@gmail.com 📞 +2348054722504, +2348128885947

https://dennisportfolio7.netlify.app/ in https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennis-okoye-9b00b71b0/

https://github.com/Okoyedennis

Summary

I am a proficient and smart fullstack developer that majors in frontend with 3+ years of development experience. I am currently working with Reactis, Typescript and Nodejs. I do my best to stay on top of changes in the software development space so that I can meet challenges with tools well suited to the job at hand.

Professional Experience

Jun 2022 - present Lagos, Nigeria

Software Developer

Access Bank Plc

- Designed APIs to allow outside application and sites to interact smoothly with websites.
- Managed software development lifecycle, leveraging project management and leadership talents.
- Maintained detailed documentation of software development processes and updates.
- Worked within Agile frameworks to consistently meet project timelines and deliverable objectives.
- Collaborated with UI/UX personnel to integrate ease-of-use and accessibility considerations into developed software.
- Leveraged design and functionality know-how to manage end-to-end website development projects.
- Worked on back end to develop server logic protocols and manage database connections.

Aug 2021 - May 2022 Lagos, Nigeria

Software Developer

Decagon Institute

- Designed user-friendly software to improve accessibility and responsiveness.
- Used established coding standards to streamline debugging, documentation and system maintenance.
- Reviewed proposed UI and UX designs for technical feasibility by collaborating with back-end development personnel.
- Continuously studied and improved abilities with wide range of web technologies, design tools and programming practices.
- Devised and implemented robust data protection and security measures.

• Updated web pages and navigation tools to meet the client's current needs and improve usability.

Dec 2019 – Jul 2021 Lagos, Nigeria

Software Developer

ANOC Services

- Integrated knowledge of application layer protocols into growing development responsibilities.
- Worked with engineering teams to define project scope and understand the planning process.
- Participated in seminars and additional training to expand knowledge and skills.
- Optimized websites to improve backward and cross-browser compatibility.
- Produced code in programming languages such as Javascript and to create the most effective and clean websites.

Skills			
• HTML	• CSS	• Javascript	• Tailwind
• Bootstrap	• React.js	• Node.js	• Express.js
• Handlebars.js	• Pug.js	• MongoDB	 Postgres
• MySQL	• Process Automation		

Other Notable Projects

Harmony Care *∂*

Role: Frontend Developer

Harmony Care Support is an organization that helps people with learning disabilities have the same fundamental rights as anyone else in society, which includes the right to develop and make informed choices about their lives.

Link: https://harmonycares.org *⊗*

Inventory Mgt App

Role: Fullstack Developer

P-Event is an inventory management application, where businessmen and women can input all stock available in their warehouses. They can track how many goods they have available, how many have been sold, out-of-stock items and lots more.

Technology Stack: React, Scss, CSS, Redux, Framer motion, node.js, mongo-db, nodemailer, cloudinary

Link: https://inventory-mgt-one.vercel.app/ ∂

Simply Group ∂

Role: Frontend Developer

Simply Group is an organization focused on the future. They're relentless about innovation and challenging the ways their customers, across all lines of business, interact with home, life, and community.

Link: https://www.mysimplygroup.com/ ⊗

Education

Sep 2015 – Sep 2019 Bachelor of Science

Anambra, Nigeria Anambra State University